# **Michael Burton**

Raleigh, NC 27606 (252) 648-1266 meburton@ncsu.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/MichaelEBurton

## **Summary**

Highly motivated individual with proven abilities working independently and collaborating in interdisciplinary teams to turn data into business insights while an intern at the Boeing Company. Experienced in public speaking while instructing small groups through leadership roles as an Eagle Scout.

## **Education**

### North Carolina State University | Raleigh, NC

Master's of Statistics May 2020

GPA: 3.92

Bachelor of Science in Statistics with a Minor in Mathematics

May 2019

Major GPA: 3.78, Cumulative GPA: 3.64

Magna Cum Laude

### **Relevant Coursework:**

Regression Analysis, Statistical Methods I & II, Experimental Design, Fundamentals of Statistical Inference I & II, Statistical Computing & Data Management, Applied Time Series Analysis, Applied Bayesian Analysis, Survey Sampling, Introduction to Statistical Learning, Matrix Theory and Linear Transformations

## **Skills & Certifications**

Certified Advanced Programmer for SAS 9 • Python • R • SQL • Unix • Git • Keras

# **Professional Experience**

The Boeing Company Seattle, WA

Data Science and Analytics Intern

May 2019 – Aug 2019

- Collaborated with an interdisciplinary team in Product Development's, Advanced Materials & Fabrication Group
- Analyzed experimental data and built predictive models using R
- Presented on the importance of tidy data and experimental design

Hanesbrands Inc. Winston-Salem, NC

Advanced Analytics Intern

Jun 2018 – Aug 2018

- Performed clustering analysis in SAS to identify informative profit segments of bra styles from 36 million data points
- Built statistical model to find optimal color mix for bra styles to grow sales and reduce excess inventory
- Reported progress in weekly staff meetings & presented results in final presentations to executive leadership
- Demonstrated ability to explain technical terminology, and methods in layman terms

#### **Environmental Protection Agency**

Durham, NC

Statistical Consultant – (Undergraduate Practicum)

Jan 2018 - May 2018

- Worked in a team to evaluate the Community Multiscale Air Quality (CMAQ) Model's Ozone predictions
- Built decision trees in SAS to evaluate where the CMAQ model inaccurately predicted Ozone levels
- Communicated with team members to create a report and presentation on findings

### **Awards & Honors**

## **Boy Scouts of America Eagle Scout Award**

Jun 2014

• Scouting's highest honor, obtained by only 2% of all scouts

#### **American Statistical Association**

Mar 2017 - Present

NCSU Student Chapter: President ('18-'19), Vice President ('17-'18)

### **Mu Sigma Rho National Statistics Honor Society**